You now know about linear regression
and gradient descent. The plan from here
你现在已经了解了线性回归和梯度下降 接下来我想
(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
on out is to tell you about a couple of
important extensions of these ideas.
给大家介绍这些概念的一些重要扩展
Concretely here they are. First it turns
out that in order to solve this
具体来讲是这样的 首先在解决这个
minimization problem, turns out there's an
algorithm for solving for theta zero and
最小化问题时 有一个算法可以直接解出theta 0和
theta one exactly without needing an
iterative algorithm. Without needing this
theta 1 而不必借助迭代 也就是梯度下降这一类
algorithm like gradient descent that we
had to iterate, you know, multiple times
要求多次迭代的算法
over. So it turns out there are advantages
and disadvantages of this algorithm that
这个算法可以让你直接求出Theta 0 和Theta 1
lets you just solve for theta zero and
theta one, basically in just one shot. One
因此也同时带来了优点和缺点
advantage is that there is no longer a
learning rate alpha that you need to worry
好处之一是你不再需要设定学习速率
about and set. And so it can be much
faster for some problems. We'll talk about
因此你可以更快地解决一些问题 关于它的其他优缺点
its advantages and disadvantages later.
Second, we'll also talk about algorithms
我们将在后面继续讨论的 其次 我们会讲到
for learning with a larger number of
features. So, so far we've been learning
应用于学习多个特征时所用的算法 至今为止
with just one feature, the size of the
house and using that to predict the price,
我们一直在只有一个特征的情况下学习 也就是用房子的大小来预测它的价格
so we're trying to take x and use that to
predict y. But for other learning problems
也就是我们试图用一个变量x来预测另一个变量y 但对于其他学习问题来说
we may have a larger number of features.
So for example let's say that you know not
我们可能会面对更多的特征作为变量 比方说 你不仅知道房子的大小
only the size, but also the number of
bedrooms, the number of floors, and the age
还知道卧室的数量 楼层数 和房子的年份
of these houses. And you want
to use that to predict the price of the
接着你想利用这些变量来预测房子的价格
houses. In that case maybe we'll call
these features x1, x2, x3, and x4. So now
在这种情况下 我们可以叫这些特征为x1 x2 x3 x4 所以现在我们就
we have, you know, four features. We want to
use these four features to predict why the
有了四个特征 我们希望使用这些特征来预测房价
price of the house. It turns out with all
of these features, four of them in this
事实上 在有多个这些特征的情况下 在此例中是四个
case, it turns out that with multiple
features it becomes harder to
想要描绘并可视化这些变量变得十分困难
plot or visualize the data. So for example
here we try to plot this type of data
比如这里 我们要想绘制这种类型的数据集
set. Maybe we will have the vertical axis
be the price and maybe we can have one
我们可以将垂直的轴标为房价
axis here, and another one here where this
axis is the size of the house, and that
将一条轴标为房子的大小
axis is the number of bedrooms. You know,
but this is just plotting, right my first
并将另一条轴标为卧室的数量 这只是描点而已 使用我们的前两个特征
two features: size and number of bedrooms.
And when we have these additional features
房子的大小和卧室数量 但是 当我们有了这些更多的特征时
I don't know, I just don't know how to
plot all of these data, right cuz I need
我就不知道如何绘制出所有的这些数据 因为我需要
like a 4-dimensional or 5-dimensional
figure. I don't really know how to plot
绘制一个四维或五维的图 我们也确实不知道如何绘制
you know something more than like a
3-dimensional figure, like, like what I
超过三维的图像 就像我这里的例子一样
have over here. Also as you can tell, the
notation starts to get a little more
另外你也一定发现了 我们使用的符号开始变得更加复杂
complicated, right. So rather than just
having x our features we now have x1
比起之前我们只有x一个特征 现在我们面对着从x1到x4
through x4. And we're using these
subscripts to denote my four different
总共4个特征 所以我们使用这些下标来区别这些不同的特征
features. It turns out the best notation
to keep all of this straight and to
事实上 我们有一套数学标记可以很好地
understand what's going on with the data
even when we don't quite know how to plot
对这些数据集进行标注 即使是在我们无法绘制它们的情况下
it. It turns out that the best notation is
the notation of linear algebra. Linear
也就是运用线性代数的符号
algebra gives us a notation and a set of
things or a set of operations that we can
线性代数赋予了我们一套符号系统和操作来进行
do with matrices and vectors. For example.
Here's a matrix where the columns of this
矩阵和向量的处理 举例来说 这里是一个矩阵 我们来看它的每一列
matrix are: The first column is the sizes
of the four houses, the second column was
第一列是四间房子的大小 第二列是
the number of bedrooms, that's the number
of floors and that was the age of the
卧室的数量 这里是楼层数 这里是房子的年份
home. And so a matrix is a block of
numbers that lets me take all of my data,
所以这个矩阵是一些数字的组合 其中包括了我们所有的数据 所有的x
all of my x's. All of my features and
organize them efficiently into sort of one
我们将所有的特征有效地组织起来 排入这样一整块的数字中
big block of numbers like that. And here
is what we call a vector in linear algebra
接着 这是我们在线性代数中所说的向量
where the four numbers here are the prices
of the four houses that we saw on the
这里的四个数字就是在之前课件上的四间房子的价格
previous slide. So. In the next set of
videos what I'm going to do is do a quick
所以 在接下来的一组视频中 我会对线性代数
review of linear algebra. If you haven't
seen matrices and vectors before, so if
进行一个快速的复习回顾 如果你从来没有接触过向量和矩阵
all of this, everything on this slide is
brand new to you or if you've seen linear
这张课件上所有的一切对你来说都是新知识
algebra before, but it's been a while so
you aren't completely familiar with it
或者你之前对线性代数有所了解 但由于隔得久了 对其有所遗忘
anymore, then please watch the next set of
videos. And I'll quickly review the linear
那就请学习接下来的一组视频 我会快速地回顾你将用到的线性代数知识
algebra you need in order to implement and
use the more powerful versions of linear
通过它们 你可以实现和使用更强大的线性回归模型
regression. It turns out linear algebra
isn't just useful for linear regression
事实上 线性代数不仅仅在线性回归中应用广泛
models but these ideas of matrices and
vectors will be useful for helping us
它其中的矩阵和向量将有助于帮助我们
to implement and actually get
computationally efficient implementations
实现之后更多的机器学习模型
for many later machines learning models as
well. And as you can tell these sorts of
并在计算上更有效率 正是因为这些
matrices and vectors will give us an
efficient way to start to organize large
矩阵和向量提供了一种有效的方式来组织
amounts of data, when we work with larger
training sets. So, in case, in case
大量的数据 特别是当我们处理巨大的训练集时
you're not familiar with linear algebra or
in case linear algebra seems like a
如果你不熟悉线性代数 如果你觉得线性代数看上去是一个
complicated, scary concept for those of you who've
never seen it before, don't worry about
复杂 可怕的概念 特别是对于之前从未接触过它的人
it. It turns out in order to implement
machine learning algorithms we need only
不必担心 事实上 为了实现机器学习算法 我们只需要
the very, very basics of
linear algebra and you'll be able to very
一些非常非常基础的线性代数知识 通过接下来几个视频
quickly pick up everything you need to
know in the next few videos.
你可以很快地学会所有你需要了解的线性代数知识
Concretely, to decide if you should
watch the next set of videos, here are the
具体来说 为了帮助你判断是否有需要学习接下来的一组视频​
topics I'm going to cover. Talk about
what are matrices and vectors. Talk about how
这里是一些我会涵盖的主题 我会讨论什么是矩阵和向量 谈谈如何
to add, subtract, multiply matrices and vectors.
Talk about the ideas of matrix inverses
加 、减 、乘矩阵和向量 讨论逆矩阵和转置矩阵的概念
and transposes. And so, if you are not
sure if you should watch the next set of
所以如果你不确定自己是否需要学习接下来的视频
videos take a look at these two things. So
if you think you know how to compute this
你可以看看这两个式子 如果你知道该如何计算这个数值
quantity, this matrix transpose times
another matrix. If you think you know, if
一个转置矩阵乘以另一个矩阵
you have seen this stuff before, if you
know how to compute the inverse of matrix
如果你之前见过这样的式子 知道如何计算一个逆矩阵
times a vector, minus a number, times
another vector. If these two things look
乘以一个向量减去一个数乘以另一个向量 如果你十分熟悉这些概念
completely familiar to you then you can
safely skip the optional set of videos on
那么你完全可以跳过这组关于线性代数的选修视频
linear algebra. But if these, concepts, if you're
slightly uncertain what these blocks of
但是如果你对这些概念仍有些许的不确定
numbers or these matrices of numbers mean,
then please take a look of the next set of
不确定这些数字或这些矩阵的意思 那么请看一看下一组的视频
videos and, it'll very quickly teach you what
you need to know about linear algebra in
它会很快地教你一些你需要知道的线性代数的知识
order to program machine learning
algorithms and deal with large amounts of data.
便于之后编写机器学习算法和处理大量数据